Never let her out of your sight. Never let your guard down. Never fall in love.
The Bodyguard is a action, drama, romance film directed by Mick Jackson.
A former Secret Service agent grudgingly takes an assignment to
protect a pop idol who's threatened by a crazed fan.
At first, the safety-obsessed bodyguard and the
self-indulgent diva totally clash.
But before long, all that tension sparks fireworks of another sort, and
the love-averse tough guy is torn between duty and romance.
Frank Farmer, played by Kevin Costner.
Rachel Marron, played by Whitney Houston.
Sy Spector, played by Gary Kemp.
Bill Devaney, played by Bill Cobbs.
Herb Farmer, played by Ralph Waite.
Greg Portman, played by Tomas Arana.
The Bodyguard is a 1992 American romantic thriller drama film directed by Mick Jackson, written by Lawrence Kasdan, and
starring Kevin Costner, Whitney Houston (in her movie acting debut), Gary Kemp, Bill Cobbs, and Ralph Waite.
The film follows a former United States Secret Service agent turned bodyguard who is
hired to protect a famous actor and singer from an unknown stalker.
Kasdan wrote the film in the mid-1970s, originally
as a vehicle for Steve McQueen.
The Bodyguard was theatrically released by Warner Bros.
Pictures on November 25, 1992.
The film grossed $411 million worldwide, becoming the second-highest-grossing
film of 1992, but received mostly unfavorable reviews from critics.
The film's accompanying soundtrack by Houston became the best-selling soundtrack album of all time, with
sales of over 45 million copies worldwide, and won the Grammy Award for Album of the Year.
The lead single "I Will Always Love You" achieved unprecedented worldwide success, selling over 24 million copies worldwide, and is
still the best-selling single in history by a woman as well as the best-selling single by a female artist of all time.
The other singles "I Have Nothing" and "Run to You" received
nominations for the Academy Award for Best Original Song.
The film received seven nominations at the 13th Golden Raspberry Awards, including for
Worst Picture, Worst Actor (for Costner) and Worst Actress (for Houston).
In spite of the Razzies, Houston received best acting nominations at the People's
Choice Awards, MTV Movie & TV Awards and the NAACP Image Awards.
Billboard later listed Houston's performance in the film as the 27th
best performance of a musician in a box-office film.
It has been reevaluated from critics and has
developed a cult following over time.
The film and soundtrack cemented Houston's status as a pop culture icon.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
bodyguard, anonymous letter, diva, stalker.
The tone is emotional.